<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.alamahant.Jasmine</id>
  <name>Jasmine</name>
  <summary>Launch websites and sessions</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      Jasmine is a comprehensive web launcher and session management application that transforms your scattered bookmarks and browser tabs into an organized, launchable workspace. Perfect for productivity enthusiasts and multi-account managers.
    </p>
    <p>
      Key Features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Smart Bookmarking: Store websites with titles, URLs, comments, favicons, and login references</li>
      <li>Session Management: Create, save, and restore multi-tab browsing sessions with one click</li>
      <li>Private Profile System: Completely isolated browsing environments for multi-account management</li>
      <li>Multi-Account Support: Simultaneously access multiple accounts on the same service without conflicts</li>
      <li>Built-in Download Manager: Complete download management with progress tracking</li>
      <li>2FA Integration: Built-in two-factor authentication code generator</li>
      <li>Screenshot Capture: Take and save screenshots of web pages for documentation</li>
      <li>Master Password Protection: Secure your data with password protection</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Perfect for managing multiple Gmail accounts, GitHub profiles, social media accounts, or any scenario where you need isolated browsing sessions. Each private profile operates as a separate browser with its own cookies, login sessions, and browsing data.
    </p>
    <p>
      Whether you're a developer managing different environments, a content creator with multiple channels, or a business manager handling client accounts, Jasmine provides unprecedented control over your online identity management.
    </p>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/Jasmine-Main.png</image>
      <caption>Main interface displaying organized bookmarks</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/Jasmine-Main-DarkTheme.png</image>
      <caption>Main Interface with Dark Theme Showing Website Cards</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/Sessions-View.png</image>
      <caption>Sessions view for managing and organizing browsing sessions</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/Sessions-View-DarkTheme.png</image>
      <caption>Sessions view with dark theme for comfortable night usage</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/WebView.png</image>
      <caption>Integrated web view for browsing websites within the application</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/Webview-Dark.png</image>
      <caption>Web view with dark theme for reduced eye strain</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/MoreSessions.png</image>
      <caption>Extended sessions management with multiple session options</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/MoreWebview.png</image>
      <caption>Advanced web view features and navigation options</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/DownloadManager.png</image>
      <caption>Built-in download manager with progress tracking</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alamahant/Jasmine/fa9112851de0bc964e11f1c93171ae52d5296b50/screenshots/2FAManager.png</image>
      <caption>Two-factor authentication manager for secure login codes</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.alamahant.Jasmine.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/alamahant/Jasmine</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/alamahant/Jasmine/issues</url>

  <developer_name>Alamahant</developer_name>

  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>WebBrowser</category>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>browser</keyword>
    <keyword>session</keyword>
    <keyword>bookmark</keyword>
    <keyword>multi-account</keyword>
    <keyword>privacy</keyword>
    <keyword>profile</keyword>
    <keyword>launcher</keyword>
    <keyword>productivity</keyword>
    <keyword>2fa</keyword>
    <keyword>download</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-info">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <releases>

<release version="1.2.2" date="2025-10-31">
  <description>
    <p>Bug Fixes and Improvements</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Subclassed QWebEnginePage and created a fully functional custom context menu with enhanced functionality and improved user experience.</li>
      <li>Ensured links opened from a tab share the same profile type as the calling tab, maintaining profile consistency across navigation and new tab operations.</li>
      <li>Performed various code optimizations, refactoring, and maintenance improvements for better performance, stability, and maintainability.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
</release>

    <release version="1.2.1" date="2025-07-23">
      <description>
        <p>Bug Fixes and Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Resolved an issue introduced with named profiles where some tabs were not saved or displayed with the correct profile when saving sessions. Now, tabs are reliably saved and shown with their associated profile—Shared Universal, Named, or Private—according to the UI profile settings at launch time.</li>
          <li>Improved security dialogs and user experience: All security-related dialogs (master password setup, password protection toggle) now include a Cancel button and properly abort the operation if Cancel or the window close (X) is pressed. This ensures that no unintended changes occur if the user cancels at any step, and toggle actions are always reverted if the process is not completed.</li>
          <li>Added pulseaudio permission to the Flatpak manifest, enabling sound playback in the application.</li>
          <li>Implemented full screen functionality for embedded and standalone videos, enhancing the media viewing experience.</li>
          <li>Added a toolbar action and F11 shortcut to instantly open a copied link from the clipboard in a new tab.</li>
          <li>Performed various code improvements and optimizations for better performance, stability, and maintainability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.2.0" date="2025-06-20">
      <description>
        <p>Major Features and Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Named Shared Profiles: Implemented contextual browsing environments allowing multiple tabs to share the same browsing context under meaningful labels like "Work," "Home," or "Research"</li>
          <li>Integrated Ad Blocker: Added comprehensive ad blocking functionality that can be toggled on/off via Tools menu</li>
          <li>Enhanced Browser Headers: Implemented custom request interceptor with standardized headers for consistent browsing experience</li>
          <li>Profile Management Tools: Added profile manager dialog for creating, deleting, and cleaning profiles with safety checks</li>
          <li>UI Improvements: Added visual indicators for active profile and enhanced profile switching experience</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.0" date="2025-06-12">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Implemented a new symlink-based storage system that dramatically reduces disk space usage</li>
          <li>Profile data now uses symbolic links instead of copying entire directories, improving performance and efficiency</li>
          <li>Added progress bar when saving sessions for better visual feedback and to prevent premature closure</li>
          <li>Implemented automatic cleanup of orphaned profile directories at startup (configurable in Tools menu)</li>
          <li>Added help documentation explaining the new storage system benefits and recommendations - users are kindly advised to read it carefully</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.1" date="2025-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>Enhanced UI and functionality improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added fully functional URL bar with toggle visibility via eye icon in toolbar</li>
          <li>New feature to create website cards directly from the currently loaded URL</li>
          <li>Set dashboard to fixed size while keeping web view resizable for improved visual quality</li>
          <li>Fixed website card update button connection to proper slot function</li>
          <li>Improved theme handling for help menu items with temporary light theme switching</li>
          <li>Fixed critical QWebEngineView resizing bugs affecting display and performance</li>
          <li>Enhanced overall application layout with better size management</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2025-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of Jasmine Website and Session Manager</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Smart bookmarking system with favicon and login reference support</li>
          <li>Complete session management with multi-tab restoration</li>
          <li>Private profile system for isolated browsing environments</li>
          <li>Multi-account support for simultaneous access to same services</li>
          <li>Built-in download manager with progress tracking</li>
          <li>Two-factor authentication (2FA) code generator</li>
          <li>Screenshot capture functionality</li>
          <li>Master password protection with SHA-256 encryption</li>
          <li>Data management and privacy controls</li>
          <li>Cross-platform Qt-based interface</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <provides>
    <binary>Jasmine</binary>
  </provides>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
  </requires>

  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
</component>












